<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fear on Essence Learning</title>
    <link>www.essencelearning.in/tags/fear/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fear on Essence Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 12:37:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.essencelearning.in/tags/fear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fear of Flying - Thunderstorm and lightning</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/15/fear-of-flying--thunderstorm-and-lightning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 12:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/15/fear-of-flying--thunderstorm-and-lightning/</guid>
      <description>Now, lets talk about the danger of flying right into the middle of the biggest and meanest thunderclouds. No competent pilot would ever do that deliberately.
What are the dangers of a thunderstorm to a plane?
Thunderstorms can have very strong winds called updrafts and downdrafts that cause what is called turbulence. Turbulence makes it very difficult to control the airplane. Wind from a thunderstorm near the ground can also be very dangerous to planes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear of Flying - Turbulence</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/14/fear-of-flying-turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 15:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/14/fear-of-flying-turbulence/</guid>
      <description>Many nervous flyers and people who are new to Aviation will be scared of turbulence. But, turbulence is nothing to worry about. In fact, turbulence is a mere annoyance to flight Crew and Passengers, as it always seems to start when we are trying to drink coffee or fill out paperwork!
WHAT IS TURBULENCE?
Turbulence is a dreaded experience for many fearful flyers, and is the source of the majority of anxiety amongst airline passengers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know flying better to overcome your fear - 1</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/12/know-flying-better-to-overcome-your-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 09:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/12/know-flying-better-to-overcome-your-fear/</guid>
      <description>IS COMMERCIAL FLYING SAFE- STATISTICS
Flying is statistically safer than almost any other mode of transport. But is this true? YES IT IS! As proof, here are a few statistics and charts:
A US National Safety Council study showed flying to be 22 times safer than travelling by car. 21,000 people (on average) die on the road in the US in a 6-month period. This is approximately the same amount of all commercial air travel fatalities WORLDWIDE in 40 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aviation is beautiful- Overcome your Fear of Flying with us</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/11/aviation-is-beautiful-overcome-your-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 13:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/11/aviation-is-beautiful-overcome-your-fear/</guid>
      <description>What is Fear of Flying?
Without getting too technical, the fear of flying is an anxiety disorder. Such fears can come about during a flight, or even well before a person gets to the airport. Often, the fear has more to do with elements of the flying experience that has little or nothing to do with the risks associated with the flight. Depending on the person, the fear of flying includes one or more of the following fears or concerns:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
