<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>requirements on Essence Learning</title>
    <link>www.essencelearning.in/categories/requirements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in requirements on Essence Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 08:37:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.essencelearning.in/categories/requirements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reference Height Chart</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2013/07/15/height-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 08:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2013/07/15/height-chart/</guid>
      <description>Feet/Inches -&amp;gt; Centimeters 4 feet 6 inches - 137 cm
4 feet 7 inches - 140 cm
4 feet 8 inches - 142 cm
4 feet 9 inches - 145 cm
4 feet 10 inches - 147 cm
4 feet 11 inches - 150 cm
5 feet 0 inches - 152 cm
5 feet 1 inches - 155 cm
5 feet 2 inches - 157 cm
5 feet 3 inches - 160 cm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Assessment</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2012/06/20/medical-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 06:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2012/06/20/medical-assessment/</guid>
      <description>CLASS-II MEDICAL ASSESSMENT ( Applicable to Cabin Crew and Airport Ground Staff). Few of the same tests are also applicable for Hotel Staff. These requirements are applicable for initial and renewal medical examinations of Personnel holding PPL, SPL, GPL, Free Balloon Pilots, Flight Radio Telephone Operators. Ultra Light Aircraft Operators and Cabin Crew Attendants.
Once a Candidate clears all the interview rounds, these medical tests are advised and upon its clearance you become a proud employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some facts about flying</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/16/some-facts-about-flying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 10:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/16/some-facts-about-flying/</guid>
      <description>HAVE YOU EVER watched a balloon as it slowly meandered upward into the sky?
The balloon is able to fly because the air within it is lighter than the surrounding air—just set it free and it’s off.
Many people think quite differently about airplanes, however. Knowing that these machines are clearly heavier than air, they might wonder what exactly keeps an airplane in the sky. And they might fear that any airplane might just fall out of the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear of Flying - Thunderstorm and lightning</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/15/fear-of-flying--thunderstorm-and-lightning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 12:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/15/fear-of-flying--thunderstorm-and-lightning/</guid>
      <description>Now, lets talk about the danger of flying right into the middle of the biggest and meanest thunderclouds. No competent pilot would ever do that deliberately.
What are the dangers of a thunderstorm to a plane?
Thunderstorms can have very strong winds called updrafts and downdrafts that cause what is called turbulence. Turbulence makes it very difficult to control the airplane. Wind from a thunderstorm near the ground can also be very dangerous to planes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear of Flying - Turbulence</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/14/fear-of-flying-turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 15:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/14/fear-of-flying-turbulence/</guid>
      <description>Many nervous flyers and people who are new to Aviation will be scared of turbulence. But, turbulence is nothing to worry about. In fact, turbulence is a mere annoyance to flight Crew and Passengers, as it always seems to start when we are trying to drink coffee or fill out paperwork!
WHAT IS TURBULENCE?
Turbulence is a dreaded experience for many fearful flyers, and is the source of the majority of anxiety amongst airline passengers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recruitment Process - Guidelines</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/04/21/reruitment-process-guideline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 15:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/04/21/reruitment-process-guideline/</guid>
      <description>Recruitment Process The recruitment process for the majority of airlines follow a common pattern: application forms or CV’s are received either online or by post. Candidates are then short-listed and invited for an interview.
The interview format will normally consist of an introduction about the airline, group work, English or maths written tests and finally a face to face interview with a panel of the interviewers. Some airlines may also require you to conduct a short presentation, details of any presentations will be explained in the invitation letter for the interview.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
