<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aviation on Essence Learning</title>
    <link>/categories/aviation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aviation on Essence Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 09:38:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/aviation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Know flying better to overcome your fear - 1</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/11/12/know-flying-better-to-overcome-your-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 09:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/11/12/know-flying-better-to-overcome-your-fear/</guid>
      <description>IS COMMERCIAL FLYING SAFE- STATISTICS
Flying is statistically safer than almost any other mode of transport. But is this true? YES IT IS! As proof, here are a few statistics and charts:
A US National Safety Council study showed flying to be 22 times safer than travelling by car. 21,000 people (on average) die on the road in the US in a 6-month period. This is approximately the same amount of all commercial air travel fatalities WORLDWIDE in 40 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aviation is beautiful- Overcome your Fear of Flying with us</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/11/11/aviation-is-beautiful-overcome-your-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 13:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/11/11/aviation-is-beautiful-overcome-your-fear/</guid>
      <description>What is Fear of Flying?
Without getting too technical, the fear of flying is an anxiety disorder. Such fears can come about during a flight, or even well before a person gets to the airport. Often, the fear has more to do with elements of the flying experience that has little or nothing to do with the risks associated with the flight. Depending on the person, the fear of flying includes one or more of the following fears or concerns:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wear off your wrinkles</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/10/01/wear-off-your-wrinkles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 13:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/10/01/wear-off-your-wrinkles/</guid>
      <description>Although all of us age, we can slow down wrinkles and keep our skin smooth and young for a long time by giving it both meticulous care and attention from both within and outside. Looking young is an essential part of the hospitality career. Dry skin is the chief cause of facial wrinkles. Dry skin requires constant attention over a period of months to turn it into a supple skin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cabin Crew Height and Weight Chart</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/06/01/cabin-crew-height-and-weight-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 20:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/06/01/cabin-crew-height-and-weight-chart/</guid>
      <description>Tables below will give you an idea of the height and weight standards for male and female cabin crew -
﻿</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth in Aviation industry</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/04/21/growth-in-aviation-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 03:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/04/21/growth-in-aviation-industry/</guid>
      <description>Good news, the industry is on a growth path in a big way. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at what markets are saying;
The massive growth capabilities shown by the Aviation industry in last few years and revival after slow down demands trained professionals with specialized skills, the right attitude and adequate knowledge. With the revival of the aviation sector, the next 10 years could see a three-fold increase in demand for skilled personnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career as a Cabin Crew</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/04/21/career-as-a-cabin-crew/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 02:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/04/21/career-as-a-cabin-crew/</guid>
      <description>Embarking on a journey to become a full fledge Cabin Crew/ Air Hostess/ Flight Attendant is an exciting journey but not without it&amp;rsquo;s challenges. Hence, it is important to be sure why, where and what the job entails in order to generate satisfaction from the career, financial and experience from the job as a cabin crew.
The objective is to provide guidance and evaluation to find out if this job is suitable for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
