<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hospitality on Essence Learning</title>
    <link>www.essencelearning.in/categories/hospitality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hospitality on Essence Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 13:01:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.essencelearning.in/categories/hospitality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indian Hotel Industry</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/16/indian-hotel-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 13:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/16/indian-hotel-industry/</guid>
      <description>The hotel industry in India thrives largely due to the growth in tourism and travel. The emergence of budget hotels in India to cater to the majority of the population who seek affordable accommodation has also materialized into an effective driver for growth. This sector will benefit due to certain Government regulations that will steer this sector towards further growth.
Hotel Industry in India 2011 begins with an overview of the travel and tourism industry in India – providing the market size and growth as well as an indication of the foreign exchange earnings by the sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Tourism and Hospitality</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/16/indian-tourism-and-hospitality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 09:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/16/indian-tourism-and-hospitality/</guid>
      <description>Tourism and Hospitality- India
India is one of the top tourist destinations in the world and tourist volumes have registered strong growth in the last five years. Tourist volumes are expected to grow at over 11% annually until 2015, with health and wellness tourism recording particularly strong growth due to the high healthcare costs in Western countries and the high-quality medical facilities offered in India.The Indian tourism sector has been experiencing a resilient phase of growth, driven by the flourishing middle class, increased spending by the foreign tourists, and synchronized administration and promotions by the Government of India to encourage ‘Incredible India’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Relation Officer (Hotels) - Job Description</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/09/guest-relation-officerhotels-job-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/09/guest-relation-officerhotels-job-description/</guid>
      <description>Front Office (Hotels)- Guest Relations Officer- Job Description Key Responsibilities Plan and coordinate the provision of friendly, efficient services to guests Schedule activities for guests Plan and coordinate all promotional activities targeting clients Trace relevant statistics about clientele Coordinate and supervise all activities for guests Assist with check-ins / check-outs of clients Greet Guests upon arrival Assist guests with airline bookings and reconfirmation’s Assist all departments in being receptive to the needs of guests Assist staff with language and culture Attend recreation activities when necessary Plan and conduct group and function rundown meetings Assist in any other duties when required by the Front Office Manager Assist with translations (information: guest directory; menus etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front Office Executive- Job Description</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/09/front-office-executive-job-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 07:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/09/front-office-executive-job-description/</guid>
      <description>Position Summary
Accommodates guests of hotel by greeting, performing guest transactions, answering the telephone, operating necessary front office equipment, etc. to ensure high-quality guest relation.
Technical or Administrative Knowledge
Must be able to add, subtract, multiply and divide. General knowledge of computers. - Special Skills and/or Abilities
Excellent interpersonal communication and customer service skills. Maintains professional appearance and demeanor at all times. Job Description (continued) Essential Functions include but not limited to the following -</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
