<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essence Learning</title>
    <link>www.essencelearning.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Essence Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 08:37:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.essencelearning.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reference Height Chart</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2013/07/15/height-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 08:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2013/07/15/height-chart/</guid>
      <description>Feet/Inches -&amp;gt; Centimeters 4 feet 6 inches - 137 cm
4 feet 7 inches - 140 cm
4 feet 8 inches - 142 cm
4 feet 9 inches - 145 cm
4 feet 10 inches - 147 cm
4 feet 11 inches - 150 cm
5 feet 0 inches - 152 cm
5 feet 1 inches - 155 cm
5 feet 2 inches - 157 cm
5 feet 3 inches - 160 cm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Assessment</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2012/06/20/medical-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 06:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2012/06/20/medical-assessment/</guid>
      <description>CLASS-II MEDICAL ASSESSMENT ( Applicable to Cabin Crew and Airport Ground Staff). Few of the same tests are also applicable for Hotel Staff. These requirements are applicable for initial and renewal medical examinations of Personnel holding PPL, SPL, GPL, Free Balloon Pilots, Flight Radio Telephone Operators. Ultra Light Aircraft Operators and Cabin Crew Attendants.
Once a Candidate clears all the interview rounds, these medical tests are advised and upon its clearance you become a proud employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duties and Responsibilities of Cabin Crew</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2012/04/22/cabin-crew-duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 11:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2012/04/22/cabin-crew-duties/</guid>
      <description>Cabin crew are also known as Flight Attendants, Air Hostess, Flight Stewards or even trolley dolly&amp;rsquo;s! They are primarily on board an aircraft for the safety and welfare of the passengers and secondly for their comfort. If there were no services of food or drink during a flight, there would still have to be a minimum presence of cabin crew for safety, which is a legal requirement.
Because cabin crew members are the face of the airline they are expected to excel in customer service and always remain friendly, approachable and enthusiastic with a good sense of self-presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchy of Flight Crew</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2012/04/19/hierarchy-of-flight-crew/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 12:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2012/04/19/hierarchy-of-flight-crew/</guid>
      <description>Hierarchy of Flight Crew
Hierarchy varies from one airline to the other. Aircraft Crew is divided into two groups- Cockpit Crew and Cabin Crew. As an Aircraft Crew, there is a captain/ Pilot/ Commander, a first officer/ Co- Pilot, possibly a second officer (or another first officer) in the cockpit then a senior cabin crew member (different airlines use different designators) and other junior crew in the cabin. Depending on the airline, more senior crew is in charge of a particular class of travel, than junior cabin crew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Hotel Industry</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/16/indian-hotel-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 13:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/16/indian-hotel-industry/</guid>
      <description>The hotel industry in India thrives largely due to the growth in tourism and travel. The emergence of budget hotels in India to cater to the majority of the population who seek affordable accommodation has also materialized into an effective driver for growth. This sector will benefit due to certain Government regulations that will steer this sector towards further growth.
Hotel Industry in India 2011 begins with an overview of the travel and tourism industry in India – providing the market size and growth as well as an indication of the foreign exchange earnings by the sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Tourism and Hospitality</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/16/indian-tourism-and-hospitality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 09:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/16/indian-tourism-and-hospitality/</guid>
      <description>Tourism and Hospitality- India
India is one of the top tourist destinations in the world and tourist volumes have registered strong growth in the last five years. Tourist volumes are expected to grow at over 11% annually until 2015, with health and wellness tourism recording particularly strong growth due to the high healthcare costs in Western countries and the high-quality medical facilities offered in India.The Indian tourism sector has been experiencing a resilient phase of growth, driven by the flourishing middle class, increased spending by the foreign tourists, and synchronized administration and promotions by the Government of India to encourage ‘Incredible India’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Relation Officer (Hotels) - Job Description</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/09/guest-relation-officerhotels-job-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/09/guest-relation-officerhotels-job-description/</guid>
      <description>Front Office (Hotels)- Guest Relations Officer- Job Description Key Responsibilities Plan and coordinate the provision of friendly, efficient services to guests Schedule activities for guests Plan and coordinate all promotional activities targeting clients Trace relevant statistics about clientele Coordinate and supervise all activities for guests Assist with check-ins / check-outs of clients Greet Guests upon arrival Assist guests with airline bookings and reconfirmation’s Assist all departments in being receptive to the needs of guests Assist staff with language and culture Attend recreation activities when necessary Plan and conduct group and function rundown meetings Assist in any other duties when required by the Front Office Manager Assist with translations (information: guest directory; menus etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front Office Executive- Job Description</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/09/front-office-executive-job-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 07:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/12/09/front-office-executive-job-description/</guid>
      <description>Position Summary
Accommodates guests of hotel by greeting, performing guest transactions, answering the telephone, operating necessary front office equipment, etc. to ensure high-quality guest relation.
Technical or Administrative Knowledge
Must be able to add, subtract, multiply and divide. General knowledge of computers. - Special Skills and/or Abilities
Excellent interpersonal communication and customer service skills. Maintains professional appearance and demeanor at all times. Job Description (continued) Essential Functions include but not limited to the following -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some facts about flying</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/16/some-facts-about-flying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 10:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/16/some-facts-about-flying/</guid>
      <description>HAVE YOU EVER watched a balloon as it slowly meandered upward into the sky?
The balloon is able to fly because the air within it is lighter than the surrounding air—just set it free and it’s off.
Many people think quite differently about airplanes, however. Knowing that these machines are clearly heavier than air, they might wonder what exactly keeps an airplane in the sky. And they might fear that any airplane might just fall out of the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear of Flying - Thunderstorm and lightning</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/15/fear-of-flying--thunderstorm-and-lightning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 12:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/15/fear-of-flying--thunderstorm-and-lightning/</guid>
      <description>Now, lets talk about the danger of flying right into the middle of the biggest and meanest thunderclouds. No competent pilot would ever do that deliberately.
What are the dangers of a thunderstorm to a plane?
Thunderstorms can have very strong winds called updrafts and downdrafts that cause what is called turbulence. Turbulence makes it very difficult to control the airplane. Wind from a thunderstorm near the ground can also be very dangerous to planes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear of Flying - Turbulence</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/14/fear-of-flying-turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 15:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/14/fear-of-flying-turbulence/</guid>
      <description>Many nervous flyers and people who are new to Aviation will be scared of turbulence. But, turbulence is nothing to worry about. In fact, turbulence is a mere annoyance to flight Crew and Passengers, as it always seems to start when we are trying to drink coffee or fill out paperwork!
WHAT IS TURBULENCE?
Turbulence is a dreaded experience for many fearful flyers, and is the source of the majority of anxiety amongst airline passengers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know flying better to overcome your fear - 1</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/12/know-flying-better-to-overcome-your-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2011 09:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/12/know-flying-better-to-overcome-your-fear/</guid>
      <description>IS COMMERCIAL FLYING SAFE- STATISTICS
Flying is statistically safer than almost any other mode of transport. But is this true? YES IT IS! As proof, here are a few statistics and charts:
A US National Safety Council study showed flying to be 22 times safer than travelling by car. 21,000 people (on average) die on the road in the US in a 6-month period. This is approximately the same amount of all commercial air travel fatalities WORLDWIDE in 40 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aviation is beautiful- Overcome your Fear of Flying with us</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/11/aviation-is-beautiful-overcome-your-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 13:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/11/11/aviation-is-beautiful-overcome-your-fear/</guid>
      <description>What is Fear of Flying?
Without getting too technical, the fear of flying is an anxiety disorder. Such fears can come about during a flight, or even well before a person gets to the airport. Often, the fear has more to do with elements of the flying experience that has little or nothing to do with the risks associated with the flight. Depending on the person, the fear of flying includes one or more of the following fears or concerns:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wear off your wrinkles</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/10/01/wear-off-your-wrinkles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 13:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/10/01/wear-off-your-wrinkles/</guid>
      <description>Although all of us age, we can slow down wrinkles and keep our skin smooth and young for a long time by giving it both meticulous care and attention from both within and outside. Looking young is an essential part of the hospitality career. Dry skin is the chief cause of facial wrinkles. Dry skin requires constant attention over a period of months to turn it into a supple skin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cabin Crew Height and Weight Chart</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/06/01/cabin-crew-height-and-weight-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 20:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/06/01/cabin-crew-height-and-weight-chart/</guid>
      <description>Tables below will give you an idea of the height and weight standards for male and female cabin crew -
﻿</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recruitment Process - Guidelines</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/04/21/reruitment-process-guideline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 15:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/04/21/reruitment-process-guideline/</guid>
      <description>Recruitment Process The recruitment process for the majority of airlines follow a common pattern: application forms or CV’s are received either online or by post. Candidates are then short-listed and invited for an interview.
The interview format will normally consist of an introduction about the airline, group work, English or maths written tests and finally a face to face interview with a panel of the interviewers. Some airlines may also require you to conduct a short presentation, details of any presentations will be explained in the invitation letter for the interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth in Aviation industry</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/04/21/growth-in-aviation-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 03:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/04/21/growth-in-aviation-industry/</guid>
      <description>Good news, the industry is on a growth path in a big way. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at what markets are saying;
The massive growth capabilities shown by the Aviation industry in last few years and revival after slow down demands trained professionals with specialized skills, the right attitude and adequate knowledge. With the revival of the aviation sector, the next 10 years could see a three-fold increase in demand for skilled personnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career as a Cabin Crew</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/04/21/career-as-a-cabin-crew/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 02:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/blog/2011/04/21/career-as-a-cabin-crew/</guid>
      <description>Embarking on a journey to become a full fledge Cabin Crew/ Air Hostess/ Flight Attendant is an exciting journey but not without it&amp;rsquo;s challenges. Hence, it is important to be sure why, where and what the job entails in order to generate satisfaction from the career, financial and experience from the job as a cabin crew.
The objective is to provide guidance and evaluation to find out if this job is suitable for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/contact/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to help Are you curious about your prospects in Aviation and Hospitality? Do you feel your calling in this field?
Please feel free to contact us, we will be happy to help you in your quest!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/courses/</guid>
      <description>Partnered with JAINx offering Skill Diploma and certificate courses along with JAIN (Deemed-to-be University) as Knowledge Partner for the courses mentioned below. You can also download detailed course information here. Aviation and Hospitality Management This course covers Inflight, Ground handling as well as hospitality management.
Eligibility: Age: Minimum 18 years and Maximum 27 years Note: Maximum limit relaxable upto 3 years for SC/ST and OBC candidates in case of Indian National carriers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/faq/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick help with most frequent queries from our visitors -
1. I cannot speak an additional language, is this going to hold me back from being hired as a cabin crew/ Airport staff? Not at all, speaking additional language is not essential to become a cabin crew/ Airport staff, although it is desirable. However fluency in English and Hindi is a must for domestic Airlines. For international Air Carriers, Fluency in English is mandatory and knowledge of any regional or foreign language is an added advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductory Pilot Training Course</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/introcourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/introcourse/</guid>
      <description>Introducing the new pilot training course Interested in our pilot training course? Schedule a callback to know more. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team</title>
      <link>www.essencelearning.in/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.essencelearning.in/team/</guid>
      <description>Godhuli Raman – Founder Godhuli is an Aviation enthusiast and a veteran who aims to play an important role in the vocational training by providing a wide range of opportunities to both our trainees and the partners to sustain and broader Aviation and Hospitality community. The industry relies on the skills and leadership of its people. Her aim is to fill the gap that exists between the current knowledge, skills, attitude etc and the competences required by the industry through imparting quality and affordable training at Essence Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
